questions = [
    {
        'question': "What command is used to list the contents of a directory in Linux?",
        'options': ['cd', 'ls', 'mkdir'],
        'correct_answer': 'ls'
    },
    {
        'question': "Which port is commonly used for SSH (Secure Shell) connections?",
        'options': ['22', '80', '443'],
        'correct_answer': '22'
    },
    {
        'question': "What does the acronym 'HTTP' stand for in the context of web communication?",
        'options': ['Hyperlink Text Transfer Protocol', 'Hypertext Transmission Protocol', 'Hypertext Transfer Protocol'],
        'correct_answer': 'Hypertext Transfer Protocol'
    },
    {
        'question': "Which tool is commonly used for network packet analysis?",
        'options': ['Metasploit', 'Wireshark', 'Nmap'],
        'correct_answer': 'Wireshark'
    },
    {
        'question': "In forensics, what does 'RAM' stand for?",
        'options': ['Read-Only Memory', 'Random Access Memory', 'Redundant Array of Memory'],
        'correct_answer': 'Random Access Memory'
    },
    {
        'question': "Which command is used to check network connectivity in Linux?",
        'options': ['ping', 'traceroute', 'netstat'],
        'correct_answer': 'ping'
    },
    {
        'question': "What is the default web server software on most Linux distributions?",
        'options': ['Lighttpd', 'Nginx', 'Apache HTTP Server'],
        'correct_answer': 'Apache HTTP Server'
    },
    {
        'question': "What type of attack involves flooding a network or server with excessive traffic to disrupt normal operation?",
        'options': ['Load Balancing attack','DDoS (Distributed Denial of Service)', 'XSS (Cross-Site Scripting)', 'SQL Injection'],
        'correct_answer': 'DDoS (Distributed Denial of Service)'
    },
    {
        'question': "Which encryption algorithm is commonly used for secure communication over the internet?",
        'options': ['AES (Advanced Encryption Standard)', 'DES (Data Encryption Standard)', 'RSA (Rivest-Shamir-Adleman)'],
        'correct_answer': 'AES (Advanced Encryption Standard)'
    },
    {
        'question': "What tool is commonly used for password cracking?",
        'options': ['dirbuster','crunch', 'Hydra', 'John the Ripper'],
        'correct_answer': 'John the Ripper'
    },
    {
        'question': "What does the acronym 'VPN' stand for?",
        'options': ['Very Private Network','Virtual Private Network', 'Verified Private Network'],
        'correct_answer': 'Virtual Private Network'
    },
    {
        'question': "Which protocol is used for secure communication over a computer network?",
        'options': ['FTP (File Transfer Protocol)', 'HTTP (Hypertext Transfer Protocol)', 'SFTP (Secure File Transfer Protocol)', 'HTTPS (Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure)'],
        'correct_answer': 'HTTPS (Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure)'
    },
    {
        'question': "What type of malware disguises itself as legitimate software?",
        'options': ['Trojan', 'Worm', 'Virus'],
        'correct_answer': 'Trojan'
    },
    {
        'question': "What command is used to change file permissions in Linux?",
        'options': ['chmod', 'chown', 'chmodx'],
        'correct_answer': 'chmod'
    },
    {
        'question': "Which file extension is commonly associated with executable files in Linux?",
        'options': ['.exe', '.bin', '.sh'],
        'correct_answer': '.sh'
    }
]
